Harold J. McMann Logbook Collection
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
Harold J. McMann Logbook Collection, 1961-2002 (#2013-0005)
McMann, Harold J.
2013-0005
25 boxes (12.5 linear feet)
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
The Harold J. McMann Logbook Collection is of logbooks covering four decades (1961-2002) reporting McMann's NASA career at the Extravehicular Activities (EVA) Office. The collection covers the activities of the Crew Systems Division at the Lane-Wells Building (MSC site 4).
Biographical Sketch
Harold Joseph "Joe" McMann, Jr. received a Bachelor of Science degree from the University of Notre Dame in 1959. He worked as a staff application engineer at Liquid Carbonic Corporation, a division of General Dynamics, until he joined NASA as an aerospace technologist for Materials, Life Systems Division, Space Task Group, in 1961. McCann held increasingly responsible positions until he became the manager of the EVA Management Office, EVA and Crew Equipment Office in 1996. He was a member of the EVA Hardware Development Group, EVA Project Office, before leaving NASA in 1996. On leaving NASA, McMann took a position as an engineer at the Hamilton Sundstrand Corporation, a position that he held in 2002. McMann received 15 awards for his work, including the MSC Outstanding Performance Award, Project Mercury; the Victor A. Prather Award; and the JSC Group Achievement Award, Manned Maneuvering Unit Thermal/Vacuum Test Support Team, JSC NITROX Development and Support Team for STS-61.
Scope and Contents Note
Logbooks covering four decades reporting the activities of the Crew Systems Division at the Lane-Wells Building (MSC Site 4)
Access Restrictions
Unrestricted
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
McMann, Harold J.
Subjects (Organizations)
Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center
Subjects
Extravehicular activity (Manned space flight); Logbooks
Places
Houston (Tex.)
Acquisition Information
Acquired from the JSC History Office
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Harold J. McMann Logbook Collection, 1961-2002
  - Logbook 1, 23 Oct. 1961-17 Dec. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 2, 18 Dec. 1962-15 May 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 3, 17 May 1963-6 Sept. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 4, 10 Sept. 1963-18 Apr. 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 5, 14 Apr. 1964-13 July 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 6, 15 July 1964-17 Oct. 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 7, 13 Oct. 1964-15 Feb. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 8, 18 Feb. 1965-17 May 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 9, 13 May 1965-1 Sept. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 10, 2 Sept. 1965-7 Jan. 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 11, 10 Jan. 1965-15 Apr. 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 12, 16 Apr. 1966-19 July 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 13, 20 Jul. 1966-10 Nov. 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 14, 14 Nov. 1966-30 Mar. 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 15, 31 Mar. 1967-14 Sept. 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 16, 15 Sept. 1967-14 Feb. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 17, 15 Feb. 1968-30 Jun. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 18, 8 Jul. 1968-5 Dec. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 19, 6 Dec. 1968-25 Mar. 1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 20, 25 Mar. 1969-11 Jul. 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 21, 14 Jul. 1969-7 Jan. 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 22, 8 Jan. 1970-21 Apr. 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 23, 22 Apr. 1970-19 Aug. 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 24, 20 Aug. 1970-3 Dec. 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 25, 7 Dec. 1970-23 Mar. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 26, 24 Mar. 1971-2 Nov. 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 27, 26 Jul. 1971-2 Nov. 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 28, 3 Nov. 1971-13 Mar. 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 29, 14 Mar. 1972-12 July 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 30, 13 July 1972-31 Oct. 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 31, 1 Nov. 1972-23 Feb. 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 32, 12 Mar. 1973-19 May 1973 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 33, 19 May 1977-8 Aug. 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 34, 9 Aug. 1973-29-Oct. 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 35, 30 Oct. 1973-23 Jan. 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 36, 24 Jan. 1974-8 May 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 37, 9 May 1974-16 Sept. 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 38, 17 Sept. 1974-19 Dec. 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 39, 20 Dec. 1974-10 Apr. 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 40, 11 Apr. 1975-8 Jul. 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 41, 9 Jul. 1975-6 Oct. 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 42, 7 Oct. 1975-13 Jan. 1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 43, 14 Jan. 1976-19 Apr. 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 44, 20 Apr. 1976-21 Sept. 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 45, 23 Sept. 1976-8 Dec. 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 46, 9 Dec. 1976-9 Mar. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 47, 10 Mar. 1977-29 Apr. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 48, 2 May 1977-20 Jun. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 49, 21 Jun. 1977-10 Aug. 1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 50, 22 Aug. 1977-22 Oct. 1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 51, 28 Oct. 1977-5 Jan. 1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 52, 6 Jan. 1978-13 Mar. 1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 53, 14 Mar. 1978-12 May 1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 54, 22 May 1978-26 July 1978 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 55, 28 Jul. 1978-6 Oct. 1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 56, 11 Oct. 1978-30 Nov. 1978 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 57, 1 Dec. 1978-8 Feb. 1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 58, 9 Feb. 1979-5 Apr. 1979 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 59, 6 Apr. 1979-29 May 1979 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 60, 30 May 1979-9 Aug. 1979 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 61, 10 Aug. 1979-10 Oct. 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 62, 11 Oct. 1979-12 Dec. 1979 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 63, 13 Dec. 1979-6 Mar. 1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 64, 7 Mar. 1980-1 May 1980 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 65, 1 May 1980-23 Jun. 1980 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 66, 24 Jun. 1980-21 Aug. 1980 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 67, 22 Aug. 1980-22 Oct. 1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 68, 23 Oct. 1980-8 Jan. 1980 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 69, 9 Jan. 1981-26 Feb. 1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 70, 27 Feb. 1981-20 May 1981 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 71, 22 May 1981-18 Aug. 1981 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 72, 19 Aug. 1981-23 Nov. 1981 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 73, 24 Nov. 1981-4 Feb. 1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 74, 1 Feb. 1982-29 Apr. 1982 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 75, 30 Apr. 1982-8 Jul. 1982 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 76, 12 Jul. 1982-27 Sept. 1982 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 77, 28 Sept. 1982-1 Dec. 1982 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 78, 2 Dec. 1982-18 Jan. 1983 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 79, 19 Jan. 1983-21 Mar. 1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 80, 23 Mar. 1983-13 May 1983 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 81, 16 May 1983-25 Aug. 1983 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 82, 29 Aug. 1983-10 Nov. 1983 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 83, 16 Nov. 1983-24 Jan. 1984 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 84, 25 Jan. 1984-3 Apr. 1984 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 85, 4 Apr. 1984-11 Jun. 1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 86, 12 Jun. 1984-3 Sept. 1984 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 87, 4 Sept. 1984-12 Nov. 1984 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 88, 14 Nov. 1984-19 Feb. 1985 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 89, 20 Feb. 1985-1 May 1985 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 90, 2 May 1985-16 Jul. 1985 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 91, 17 Jul. 1985-26 Sept. 1985 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 92, 27 Sept. 1985-30 Nov. 1985 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 93, 2 Dec. 1985-4 Mar. 1986 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 94, 5 Mar. 1986-23 May 1986 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 95, 23 May 1986-19 Aug. 1986 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 96, 20 Aug. 1986-14 Nov. 1986 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 97, 17 Nov. 1986-27 Feb. 1987 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 98, 2 Mar. 1987-8 May 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 99, 11 May 1987-21 Aug. 1987 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 100, 1 Sept. 1987-10 Dec. 1987 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 101, 11 Dec. 1987-5 Apr. 1988 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 102, 6 Apr. 1988-21 Jun. 1988 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 103, 22 Jun. 1988-10 Aug. 1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 104, 11 Aug. 1988-21 Oct. 1988 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 105, 24 Oct. 1988-17 Jan. 1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 106, 18 Jan. 1989-15 Mar. 1989 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 107, 16 Mar. 1989-4 May 1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 108, 5 May 1989-10 Jul. 1989 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 109, 11 Jul. 1989-12 Sept. 1989 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 110, 13 Sept. 1989-13 Nov. 1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 111, 14 Nov. 1989-22 Jan. 1990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 112, 23 Jan. 1990-19 Mar. 1990 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 113, 20 Mar. 1990-18 May 1990 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 114, 21 May 1990-7 Aug. 1990 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 115, 8 Aug. 1990-16 Oct. 1990 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 116, 17 Oct. 1990-14 Jan. 1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 117, 15 Jan. 1991-25 Mar. 1991 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 118, 26 Mar. 1991-21 May 1991 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 119, 22 May 1991-21 Aug. 1991 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 120, 21 Aug. 1991-28 Oct. 1991 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 121, 29 Oct. 1991-16 Jan. 1992 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 122, 17 Jan. 1992-30 Mar. 1992 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 123, 31 Mar. 1992-10 Jun. 1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 124, 11 Jun. 1992-21 Aug. 1992 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 125, 25 Aug. 1992-9 Nov. 1992 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 126, 10 Nov. 1992-8 Feb. 1993 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 127, 9 Feb. 1993-22 Apr. 1993 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 128, 23 Apr. 1993-29 Jun. 1993 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 129, 30 Jun. 1993-13 Sept. 1993 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 130, 14 Sept. 1993-26 Nov. 1993 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 131, 29 Nov. 1993-23 Feb. 1994 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 132, 24 Feb. 1994-13 May 1994 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 133, 16 May 1994- 3 Aug. 1994 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 134, 4 Aug. 1994-20 Oct. 1994 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 135, 21 Oct. 1994-27 Jan. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 136, 30 Jan. 1995-12 Apr. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 137, 13 Apr. 1995-19 July 1995 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 138, 20 July 1995-3 Oct. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 139, 4 Oct. 1995-6 Dec. 1995 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 140, 7 Dec. 1995-26 Feb. 1996 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 141, 27 Feb. 1996-24 Apr. 1996 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 142, 25 Apr. 1996-25 Jun. 1996 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 143, 26 Jun. 1996-27 Aug. 1996 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Logbook 144, 28 Aug. 1996-4 Nov. 1996 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Logbook 159-R15, 12 Jan. 2001-2 May 2001 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Logbook 160-R16, 3 May 2001-7 Aug. 2001 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Logbook 161-R17, 8 Aug. 2001-29 Nov. 2001 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Logbook 162-R18, 3 Dec. 2001-14 Mar. 2002 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Logbook 163-R19, 15 Mar. 2002-19 Nov. 2002 (Box 25, Folder 5)